Subject: [SIG-IRList] 1st CFP: JAIR Special Track on Cross-language Algorithms and Applications


JAIR Special Track on Cross-language Algorithms and Applications

 
Track Editor
Lluís Màrquez, Qatar Computing Research Institute

Associate Track Editors
Marta R. Costa­jussà, Instituto Politécnico Nacional
Srinivas Bangalore, AT&T Labs-Research
Patrik Lambert, Universitat Pompeu Fabra
Elena Montiel-Ponsoda, Universidad Politécnica de Madrid


The Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research (JAIR) is pleased to announce the launch of the Special Track on Cross-language Algorithms and Applications. The core Artificial Intelligence technologies of speech and natural language processing need to address the challenges of processing multiple languages. While the first challenge of multilingualism is to bridge the nomenclature gap for the same concepts, the next significant challenge is to develop algorithms and applications that not only scale to multiple languages but also leverage cross-lingual similarities for improved natural language processing.

The goal of this special track is to serve as a home for the publication of leading research on Cross-language Algorithms and Applications, focusing on developing unified themes leading to the development of the science of multi- and cross-lingualism.  Topics of interest include, but are not limited to: efforts in the direction of multilingual transliteration; multilingual document summarization; rapid prototyping of cross language tools for low resource languages; and machine translation.

Articles published in the Cross-language Algorithms and Applications track must meet the highest quality standards as measured by originality and significance of the contribution and clarity of presentation. Papers will be coordinated by the track editor and associate editors, and reviewed by peer reviewers drawn from the JAIR Editorial Board and the larger community. All articles should be submitted using the normal JAIR submission process. Please indicate that the submission is intended for the Special Track in the section "Special Information for editors".

 
For more information and submission instructions, please see:
http://www.jair.org/specialtrack-claa.html

 

Timetable

1st March 2015                  Deadline for Submissions
1st June 2015                    Notification of Acceptance/Revision/Rejection
15th July 2015                   Deadline for Re-submission of papers requiring revision
15th September 2015        Notification of Final Acceptance
1st November 2015           Final manuscript due

Contact: martaruizcostajussa@gmail.com

Submission Instructions: Use JAIR conventional submissions instructions available at http://www.jair.org/submission_info.html





